[panting]
>> Should I be writing any of this down?
>> No.
>> Wait.
Does that guy have six fingers?
>> The machine knew what a hand looked
like. It just had no idea how to count.
>> So, why not fix it?
>> [laughter]
>> Her face keeps melting.
She's not She isn't blinking.
>> Every frame is a stranger doing an
impression of the last one.
>> And you fixed that?
>> We stopped feeding it flat [music]
pictures.
Started teaching it how the world
actually works.
Light,
weight,
what happens when something [music]
falls.
>> There's no glass.
>> You only need glass [music] for the
things that break when you look too
close.
>> Is he real?
Are you asking me
or her?
>> Now, in this video, I will show you
step-by-step how to master AI realism.
This video is sponsored by Hicksfield,
so if you want to follow along, make
sure to click the link in the
description down below. There you can
try out Seedance 2.5 for yourself along
with all of the other tools that we'll
be using in this video. So, the first
thing that we need to get straight is
what actually makes a video look
realistic. And in particularly, what
makes an AI video feel real or fake. Now
to explain this, take a look at this
graph. This is called the uncanny
valley. This, in summary, explains why
sometimes it feels off. We can see it
goes from a robot to a cartoon character
to a stylized humanoid. And then there
is a dip. That's called the uncanny
valley. When it's too real, too human,
it feels off. It needs to have that
human element into it. And that is the
thing that most people overlook when
making AI images because it's too
polished, it's too perfect. And that's
when you miss that spot. It can be the
movement, it can be the flaws. It just
starts to feel strange and creepy. And
that is what a lot of people have with
AI. So to avoid that, we need to get
that human realness into our prompts.
And the uncanny valley doesn't just
apply to AI. It also applies to humans
that look too symmetrical or too
perfect.
>> I thought you were AI.
>> Because realism is imperfection, and
that's what we're going to create. So
how do we create that imperfection? It
is all about using the right models and
the correct prompts. Now, let me first
talk about the models. Take a look at
these images. All of these were
generated with the same model. Can you
guess which model I used for this? It's
not GPT image 2, and it's not Seedream
5.0 Pro. This was created using
Hicksfield Soul. And not because this
video was sponsored by Hicksfield, it's
actually because this model really
focuses on creating cinematic type
images of people. It does super well at
that. I don't know what they trained
this with, but with all of the
imperfections that these people have, it
starts to look human. So, this was
simply made by using this short prompt
and I will go in detail later about the
prompt and you can find all the prompts
that I used in my free school community
where you can copy them and check them
out for yourself at your own pace. And
that gave me this result. Like we have
all of the imperfections on this guy's
face. It's not fully sharp. There's a
bit of stuff like on his jacket. He has
bags under his eyes. He has wrinkles. He
doesn't have the best hairline, neither
do I, but that is what makes us human.
>> [music]
>> Now, if you want to generate a video, I
would recommend creating a character
sheet of your character. So, we're going
to use this as a reference. Now, we have
to retype or prompt. For that, I'm using
a pretty simple prompt which I also will
share with you in the asset file. So,
this is the prompt that we're using for
that. And normally, I would create this
with GPT image 2, but while I was doing
my research and also while I was looking
at all of the images that I generated, I
by now can tell when an image is
generated using GPT image 2 because it
is way too noisy. And especially with
image and video generation, each time
the image gets slightly worse in my
opinion. I'm now using SeaArt 5.0 Pro
when I generate these character sheets.
You can do this in up to 2K. You can
choose the aspect ratio. I'm actually
going to do 16:9 and then you can
generate your images. This looks a
little bit sharper. It looks a little
bit more polished, but I don't mind it.
We have a good close-up of his face. I
removed the hat right here. The reason
for that is because this is a small hat
and you don't want to have the AI use
such small details when it makes videos
because if you do that, then it's not
going to look sharp. It's not going to
look real. It might even change the
characteristics of your character. And
now that we have our character sheet,
we're going to upload that in the prompt
box again. Then, I'm also going to add
in my original character just so that I
have an extra reference of him. I'm not
going to take it. I just added it in
there. And I say, "Image one is used for
his identity." Then, I'm basically
adding in a bunch of details of what
this guy looks like. And I'm adding in
do not recast, do not beautify, do not
use as an image background. Then we're
going to describe what we want him to
look like in our first starting frame.
And then the final touch is adding in
the lens details. So here I'm saying
it's shot on a 35 mm lens, aperture of
1.8, shallow depth of field, visible
fine film grain, muted desaturated color
grade. These are like film or camera
instructions. More on that later. And
then you're going to hit generate and
then you have your first image. And this
is what's needed to have the baseline
for your videos. So don't underestimate
your images because this is the part
where you could save so much time and
credits [music] to get your character to
look cinematic. If your starting frame
or your reference doesn't look
cinematic, you can still achieve
cinematic realistic videos, but it's
going to be a little bit harder. So put
in some real effort onto this. Because
if I now add in a video prompt, we're
going to get something like this.
>> I grew up on this water.
You learn the weather before you learn
the roads.
My father was a captain.
He used to say the harbor tells you when
it wants to be left alone.
And when he came home, he would
>> So yeah, rest in peace, that car. The
thing is about videos like these, it's
not just the image quality or the video
quality that makes the video real. The
thing that plays a huge role here is
[music] the dialogue. Here's an example
of what good dialogue will do to your AI
generation.
>> I'm sorry. I don't I I don't know what
to say.
>> Stop. Just stop talking.
>> I'LL TALK IF I WANT.
>> [gasps]
>> Leave him alone.
>> Why won't you stop it?
>> LEAVE ME ALONE.
>> WHY?
>> BECAUSE I LOVE YOU. [screaming]
>> This is still not perfect, but for
contrast, here's what the average AI
generation looks like in terms of
dialogue.
>> I can't keep doing this anymore.
>> You know I love you more than anything.
>> So, how do we achieve good dialogue? The
first thing you need to learn is how to
prompt like a director. Especially now
with students 2.5, it is so much better
at understanding what you want to see on
the screen than it was with previous
models. Let's analyze the first example.
So, it starts with a broken apology. It
is a continuous take, and if we look at
the prompt, then we can see in the first
stage, that is the bedroom to the living
room,
>> [music]
>> the apology. We are describing this with
a lot of different words what we want to
see there. So, the man and the woman are
walking out of a dim bedroom together,
both unsteady on their feet, into the
open living room lit by a single warm
lamp. They're alone in the house, no one
else is present. Then the primary event
is they stop in the middle of the living
room close to each other. The man speaks
first, quiet and broken, eyes wet,
struggling to get the words out. An
apology with no real explanation behind
it. Before he can finish, the woman cuts
him off sharply, telling him to stop
talking. Her face already tight with
anger. And the end state of this scene
is that the two are close together in
the living room, him mid-sentence and
glassy-eyed, her jaw clenched, having
just cut him off. So, that is explaining
to the actor [music] what you want to
see on the screen. That includes the
action, the words they need to say, the
shift in the tone, but also the pauses
that they need to add in there. And
lastly, the emotion at these moments. C
dance 2.5 does a phenomenal job at
understanding how that scene plays out.
So, you just need to find the words to
throw at the AI to help it [music] act
out your scene. But, those are not the
only ways to improve your dialogue.
Another thing that you can do is adding
in an accent. You don't just want to
write out add in an Irish accent or a
Jamaican accent. That's not going to
give you a result like this.
>> See how quiet it stay? I tell you
already, nothing out here, just bird.
Wait. Wait. Bombaclat.
You seeing this?
>> To achieve something like that, you
first want to name the speaker. Then,
you're going to include the region from
where they're from, the pace, the
energy, the emotional state, and then
their exact line. [music] So, to achieve
that accent, I first described who my
main character is. Then, I described
what his accent [music] is. So, I named
him Clement. He speaks English with an
unhurried Kingston accent, natural, not
exaggerated, not a comedy voice. When
the shock hits, the voice jumps and the
words get short. And because I've added
like more detail about what this guy is,
C dance has a good idea of like what
this guy potentially sounds like. One
thing that's very important that in your
prompt structure, you can use symbols to
[music] point out what this person is
saying. So, for dialogue, you use these
brackets, which will help C dance 2.5 to
understand that that is text that needs
to be said by your character. But, more
on that later when we get to sound.
There's just so much more to the
dialogue that I now have to tell you
about. Because, for example, you also
have acting performance words. [music]
They are simply words that describe the
state of being of your character in
terms of how he has to act. So, for
example, I have this image right here of
this guy being chased by a T-Rex. Then,
we can use the action and the
performance words. So, for example, we
can say he's riding happily with loose
shoulders and a broad smile. Then we can
say here's the footstep. He loses the
smile and he tightens the fingers. Then
he looks behind slowly and reluctantly.
[music] He freezes and screams
involuntarily. And he's pedaling with a
frantic uneven force. He leaves behind
the bicycle and he hides. Then lastly,
he's covering his mouth and he's
remaining rigidly still. He's waiting
for the footsteps to recede and then he
releases one shaky [music] breath. If we
generate that then we get a result like
this.
>> [snorts]
[groaning]
[snorts]
>> I do want to note that this is a
four-page prompt. And everything I just
said is included in that prompt in terms
of the action words that describe what's
going on. So [music] again, if you want
to go through this yourself, then please
do because that gives you a good
understanding of how to prompt for
[music] something like this. Now, the
action words is what describes what your
character needs to do. Now, let's
[music] change the way of how they feel.
So, for that we need to express emotion.
We can do various subtle emotions to
explosive ones. You can also describe a
certain trigger that causes an emotion
or [music] an action or even a visual.
If you want to know how to prompt for
your own emotions, I've created this
website for you. And it has 25 different
emotions that you can use right away and
you can just copy them. When it comes to
directing, it's not just directing the
actors how to speak, how to perform.
It's also about the camera work. And
that is something that's hugely
underrated that you need to understand.
You literally have to learn traditional
filmmaking. Because if you want to
achieve true realism, you need to know
how the camera moves, where the camera
focuses on, and how it shows its
subject. Let me break down all three of
them. So, first of all, we have camera
focus. Here you need to describe to the
AI what to focus on. So, is it your main
subject or is it your secondary subject?
Be intentional with where you want to
have the camera focus on. So, here we
have our main subject and then we
perform a deliberate rack focus on the
thing behind
And we also set up triggers. So, for
example, in this case, after he crawls,
then we see the focus change.
The next thing you need is realistic
camera movement.
>> Let me talk about camera movement.
This is a crash zoom, handheld,
raw,
chaotic,
alive.
Tracking shot.
You're right there with them.
Orbit shot. The reveal. The moment that
changes everything.
Camera movement isn't style.
>> It's emotion.
>> If you want to learn how to prompt
realistic camera movement, then take a
look at this website that I created
earlier, where I share all of the
prompts that I've used for realistic
camera movement. Another thing that will
set you apart as an AI filmmaker is
knowing how to create good camera
angles.
>> Hey, [screaming] stop!
>> Okay, let's break down that shot. We're
starting off with an establishing shot
first. This establishes the three-lane
layout. Immediately, you have a great
overview of where I am, what I am
running on, and what's going on. Then we
focus on the character. We keep tighter
framing like the shoe insert, and the
snow cam shifts the focus on the street
to my exhaustion, strain, and tunnel
vision. Then I motivate the desperation
by altering between myself and the
truck, which reinforces the widening
gap. Then we keep the action readable.
We're using uninterrupted static wide
shots for the bike as I tackle that.
We're not introducing distracting cuts
there. Then it all escalates. The
camera's dropping to a low mounted
camera bar rigs, and there's a final
sprint that is very aggressive. Choosing
those different camera angles brings
that scene to life. So, that's what you
also got to think about when you have
something in your head. The final layer
that brings everything together is the
sound. I've already showed you these
symbols that you can use to reference
your sounds. But, how does it actually
work in action, and how do you need to
prompt that? Let me show you. There are
two things that you can do. You can just
focus on diegetic sounds. Those are
sounds that the characters also hear,
and you can focus on non-diegetic
sounds. These are things like music or
extra bass or extra sound effects that
your characters won't necessarily hear,
but the audience will hear that when
watching your movie. So, here's an
example of diegetic sounds.
>> Don't come up. I'm already leaving.
>> So, for that example, we particularly
focused on these symbols. So, we added
it in there, and we basically described
what's going on. So, we have a soft
hydraulic door that's closing with a
hiss with a heavy steel door slam. Then
we have each step produces a one closed
rubber sole squeak followed immediately
by one small wet splash beneath the
corresponding foot. We describe in great
detail how we want to have that sound.
Now, here is another example where we
also use non-diegetic sounds.
>> STOP FOLLOWING ME.
>> SO, IN THIS PROMPT, we've used all three
of these different symbols. We used the
normal bracket for the music. Then we
use the other symbol, I don't know what
to call this, for the footsteps. And
then we used different bracket symbol
for what she's saying. If you look at
this and if you analyze this, then this
is something that you could do in your
prompt. So, you want to say like we have
a sharp electrical buzz click as the
light dies. Then we have a hard
non-diegetic sub-bass hit that lands on
the exact frame the light goes dark. So,
that is if we listen to that again,
that's added bass in there, added sound
that the character won't necessarily
hear, but it makes it more dramatic for
you and it makes it more that you're
into the moment and that you're dragged
into this movie. The great thing about
this, but also the really difficult part
of this, is that you really have to
think about what you want to have in
your generation. That's why I always
tell you is that you really need to go
through your prompt before you hit
generate. Otherwise, you're just wasting
generations, you're wasting credits,
wasting money, and you're wasting your
time. If the sound effects from Sea
Dance aren't good enough, then you can
also do the next thing, which is
editing. So, for editing, I have this
example that I want to share with you.
Let's take a look at the original clip.
>> Trust your vision.
Don't let the AI direct your art.
>> So for me, that clip was quite good. I
just didn't like a few things. So the
first thing I didn't like was this slow
motion of this guy jumping down. Like
that makes it unbelievable to me. The
first thing I always do is I start to
trimming up my clip in terms of each
different shot that has been used. So
let's talk first about that segment
where we have this slow motion.
To me, we don't need this dramatic slow
motion. What we just can do is we can
make a cut like right about here where
we see this guy jumping off. Then we
make a cut
and then we go up until this point.
[music] So that part entirely removed.
Now if we play this together, it's a lot
faster. That's what I like. So that's
the first thing I do. I trim up the
parts that I don't want. Then the second
thing I do is adding in zoom ins and
zoom outs. So here I started off by
zooming in. Like if we turn this off,
then we can see this is the original
clip where I zoomed in a little bit and
at the end I zoomed out. So you can see
over if we play this that it's slowly
like zooming out that reveals more of
the scene. Now for this next scene, I
zoom in a little bit because I want it
to be more dramatically focused on that
eye. So at the beginning, I keep it at
100. Then near the end, I keep it at 120
almost and that gives for a slow
dramatic zoom in and you're really
drawing the attention to that eye. Once
you've added in all of your zoom ins and
your zoom outs, there are a few
additional things that you can do. One
thing that comes to mind with a lot of
these AI scenes, it seems a bit too like
perfect, too plastic almost. What you
could do is you could go over and add in
like a effect. And for this one, we're
going to add in a bit of noise. So, you
can drag over a bit of noise on your
clip, and you can see it right here. And
then, you can change and play around
with the intensity until you get
something that you like. I wouldn't do
it too much, just like a little bit to
make sure your scene looks a bit more
realistic. And you can adjust that for
each clip, or you can add that at the
beginning of your original clip. And the
second thing you can do is you can add
in a blur. So, you can add in a blur
over your scene, and that allows you to
blur the edges a little bit. So, by
doing so, it becomes a bit more like it
was shot on a camera. And the last thing
you can do is you can add in some cinema
bars. So, for example, if you crop the
top, you can see you can adjust this,
you can play around with this. I would
do like 10 to 15%, and then once you
have done that for both sides, on the
top and the bottom right here, then you
have these cinema bars.
>> Trust your vision.
Don't let the AI direct your art.
>> So, those are small little tweaks that
you can do to make your video look more
real. Especially the noise plays a huge
part in making it look more believable.
If this was useful to you, please leave
a comment down below and tell me which
feature or which technique I showed you
you liked the most. And also, let me
know what you want me to show next. Make
sure to click the video that's on the
screen right now if you want to see more
videos about SORA 2.5.